When that Vallabhacharya persisted, he said also, "I can give so many explanations
Cuando ese Vallabhacharya continuó, dijo también, "Puedo dar tantas explicaciones
of different Names of Krishna".
de los distintos Nombres de Krsna".
[Quality Over Quantity]
Calidad por encima de la Cantidad
And Mahaprabhu said, "I only know... two: Yashodanandan and Shyamasundar.
Y Mahaprabhu dijo, "Yo sólo conozco...dos: Yashodanandana y Shyamasundar,
In fact I'm incapable of knowing more".
de hecho soy incapaz de conocer más".
What does that mean?
¿Qué signifado tiene esto?
He says, "nāmnām akāri bahudhā nija-sarva-śaktis" —
El dice, "nāmnām akāri bahudhā nija-sarva-śaktis" —
"Krishna has unlimited names", certainly not [two].
"Krishna tiene nombres ilimtados", ciertamente no sólo (2).
But He is saying, "No, I only know two".
pero afirma, "No, yo sólo conozco dos".
He is talking about a particular quality.
Él habla de una cualidad particular.
And also the implication is that
E incluso las implicaciones de ello
if you are not focused on quality,
si no estas enfocado en la calidad,
then you are going to be searching for quantity.
entonces estaras buscando la cantidad.
So Rupa Goswami advises,
Así que Rupa Goswami advierte,
"Don't initiate many disciples, don't make many temples
"No inicies muchos discípulos, no hagas muchos templos
and don't read many books".
y no leas demasiados libros".
He has told this would be... detrimental,
Ha dicho que esto podría ser... perjudicial,
detrimental to the culture of pure devotion.
perjudicial para el cultivo de la devoción pura.